Preliminary Guide to the Jody Jones Hunter Collection of Works by Anne Tyler, 1958-1998
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jody Jones Hunter Collection of Works by Anne Tyler 1958-1998
Hunter, Jody Jones
3.6 linear feet Extent: 82 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00597
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Jody Jones Hunter Collection of Works by Anne Tyler was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2001.
Biographical Note
Hunter is a collector of works by certain southern authors taught by William Blackburn. Tyler is a Duke alumna and Pulitzer Prize-winning novelist and short story writer, whose best-known works include novels The Accidental Tourist (1985) and Breathing Lessons (1988).
Collection Overview
The collection consists primarily of first editions, limited editions, translations, and other editions (many of them autographed or inscribed, 1965-1998) of the works of Anne Tyler, delineating her prolific career. Also includes books about or containing contributions by Tyler (1958-1993); issues of periodicals containing her contributions or reviews of her work (1965-1996); and three pieces of her original correspondence (1979-1989).
Subject Headings
Tyler, Anne; Hunter, Jody Jones; American literature -- 20th century; American literature -- Southern States; Authors, American -- Southern States; Authors, American -- 20th century; Authors, American -- Correspondence; Literature -- History and criticism; American fiction -- Women authors; Short Stories, American -- Women authors
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2001-0058
  - Books by Anne Tyler
    - If Morning Ever Comes (Box 1)
      - First UK edition, signed; Chatto and Windus, 1965 (Box 1)
      - Second UK edition; Severn House, 1984 (Box 1)
    - The Tin Can Tree
      - Knopf, 1965 (Box 1)
      - Macmillan, 1966 (Box 1)
    - A Slipping-Down Life
      - First edition, inscribed; Knopf, 1970 (Box 1)
      - First UK hardcover edition; Severn House, 1983 (Box 1)
    - The Clock Winder
      - First edition; Knopf, 1972 (Box 1)
      - First UK edition; Chatto and Windus, 1973 (Box 1)
    - Celestial Navigation
      - First edition; Knopf, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Searching for Caleb
      - First edition; Knopf, 1976 (Box 1)
      - First UK edition, signed; Chatto and Windus, 1976 (Box 1)
      - A La Recherche de Caleb, first French edition; Stock, 1981 (Box 2)
    - Earthly Possessions
      - First edition, inscribed; Knopf, 1977 (Box 2)
      - First UK edition; Chatto and Windus, 1977 (Box 2)
      - Toujours Partir, first French edition; Stock, 1979 (Box 2)
      - Possessi Terreni, first Italian edition; Ugo Guanda, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Morgan's Passing
      - Uncorrected proof of first edition, tall format; Knopf, 1980 (Box 2)
      - First edition; Knopf, 1980 (Box 2)
      - First UK edition, signed; Chatto and Windus, 1980 (Box 2)
      - Morgan L'Insaisissable, first French edition; Stock, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Dinner at the Homesick Restaurant
      - First edition, signed; Knopf, 1982 (Box 2)
      - First UK edition, signed; Chatto and Windus, 1982 (Box 2)
      - Le Dejeuner de la Nostalgie, first French edition; Stock, 1983 (Box 2)
      - Uncorrected proof of the first edition; Knopf, 1982 (Box 3)
      - Uncorrected proof of the first edition, bound upside-down, signed; Knopf, 1982 (Box 3)
      - Restaurang Hemlangtan, reprint of first Swedish edition; ManPocket, 1983 (Box 3)
    - The Accidental Tourist
      - Uncorrected proof, first state; Knopf, 1985 (Box 3)
      - Uncorrected proof, second state; Knopf, 1985 (Box 3)
      - First edition, signed on a tipped-in leaf; Knopf, 1985 (Box 3)
      - First UK edition, Chatto and Windus, 1985 (Box 3)
      - Den Till Fallige Turisten, first Swedish edition; Bokforlaget Trevi, 1986 (Box 3)
      - Turist Ved et Tilfaelde, first Danish edition; Gyldendal, 1986 (Box 3)
      - Le Voyageur Malgre Lui, first French edition; Stock, 1987 (Box 3)
      - Voyageur Malgre Lui, first mass market French edition with variant title; Stock, 1989 (Box 3)
      - Turista Por Acidente, first Portuguese edition; Dom Quixote, 1987 (Box 3)
      - Nakljucni Popotnik, first Slovenian edition; Salazba Mladinska knjinga, 1990 (Box 3)
    - Breathing Lessons (Box 4)
      - True first edition, original leather, signed with a special 2-page message not included in other editions; Franklin Library, 1988 (Box 4)
      - Uncorrected proof of first trade edition; Knopf, 1988 (Box 4)
      - Uncorrected proof, copy for presentation, signed on extra blank leaf bound at front; Knopf, 1988 (Box 4)
      - Signed copy; Knopf, 1988 (Box 4)
      - Ejercicios Respiratorios, first Spanish edition; Editorial Lumen, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Saint Maybe
      - First trade edition, signed on tipped-in leaf; Knopf, 1991 (Box 4)
      - First UK edition; Chatto and Windus, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Your Place is Empty
      - First separate edition, number 34 of 40 hardbound, signed; William B. Ewert, 1992 (Box 4)
      - First separate edition, number 19 of 60 handsewn, signed; William B. Ewert, 1992 (Box 4)
    - Tumble Tower
      - First edition of children's book; Orchard Books, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Ladder of Years
      - Uncorrected proof; Knopf, 1995 (Box 4)
      - First trade edition, signed on tipped-in leaf; Knopf, 1995 (Box 5)
    - A Patchwork Planet
      - First trade edition; Knopf, 1998 (Box 5)
    - The Best American Short Stories 1983
      - Edited by Tyler; uncorrected proof, signed; Houghton Mifflin, 1983 (Box 5)
      - Edited by Tyler; first edition; Houghton Mifflin, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Books Containing Contributions by Tyler and Books About Tyler
    - Freshman Writing: Essays by Students in English 1 and 2 at Duke University (Box 5)
      First and only printing, thought to be Tyler's first appearance in print; 1958-1959
    - The Young Writer at Work (Box 5)
      By Jessie Rehder, second printing; Odyssey Press, 1962
    - Under Twenty-Five: Duke Narrative and Verse, 1945-1962 (Box 5)
      William Blackburn, ed., first edition, includes first publication of I Never Saw Morning; Duke University Press, 1963
    - A Duke Miscellany: Narrative and Verse of the Sixties (Box 5)
      William Blackburn, ed., first edition, signed by Tyler; Duke University Press, 1970
    - Works in Progress, Number Six (Box 5)
      Martha Saxton, ed.; Literary Guild/Doubleday, 1972
    - The Best American Short Stories 1977 (Box 5)
      Martha Foley, ed., first edition; Houghton Mifflin, 1977
    - First Person Singular (Box 5)
      Joyce Carol Oates, ed., first edition; Ontario Review Press, 1983
    - The Available Press/Pen Story Collection (Box 5)
      First edition, introduction by Tyler; Available Press/Ballantine, 1985
    - Contemporary American Women Writers (Box 5)
      Catherine Rainwater and William J. Scheick, eds., first edition; University Press of Kentucky, 1985
    - Art and the Accidental in Anne Tyler (Box 5)
      By Joseph C. Voelker, first edition; University of Missouri Press, 1989
    - Louder Than Words: 23 Authors Donate New Stories to Benefit Share Our Strength's Fight Against Hunger, Homelessness and Illiteracy (Box 6)
      William Shore, ed.; Vintage, 1989
    - Birch Lane Press Presents American Fiction: The Best Unpublished Stories by Emerging Writers (Box 6)
      Michael C. White and Alan Davis, eds., introduction by guest judge Tyler; uncorrected proof; Birch Lane Press, 1990
    - The Fiction of Anne Tyler (Box 6)
      C. Ralph Stephens, ed., first edition; University Press of Mississippi, 1990
    - Forward Into the Past: For May Sarton on her Eightieth Birthday May 3, 1992 (Box 6)
      Susan Sherman, ed., limited edition; William B. Ewert, 1992
    - Anne Tyler (Box 6)
      By Elizabeth Evans, first edition, signed by Tyler and Evans; Tawyne, 1993
    - The Book of Absent People (Box 6)
      By Taghi Modarressi (Tyler's husband), first edition; Doubleday, 1986
  - Periodicals Containing Contributions by Tyler
    - The Southern Review
      - Vol. 1, No. 2, Spring (April) 1965 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 3, No. 1, Winter 1967 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 3, No. 1, Winter 1967 (copy 2) (Box 6)
      - Vol. 11, No. 3, Summer (July) 1975 (Box 6)
    - The New York Times Book Review
      - 15 June 1986; He Did It All for Jane Elizabeth Firesheets, first publication of Tyler's review of Off for the Sweet Hereafter by T. R. Pearson (Box 6)
      - 14 April 1991; Tribal Rites in Westchester, first publication of Tyler's review of Object Lessons by Anna Quindlen (Box 6)
    - The Atlantic
      - Vol. 268, No. 4, October 1991; In the Land of the Lolita, first publication of Tyler's review of Vladimir Nabokov: The American Years by Brian Boyd (Box 6)
    - The Algonkian
      - New Series No. 3, January 1996; Introduction: Best of the South, expanded version published in the actual book Best of the South, Shannon Ravenel, ed. (Box 6)
  - Reviews of Tyler's Books
    - The New York Times Book Review
      - 8 Sept. 1985; Life is a Foreign Country, review of The Accidental Tourist by Larry McMurtry (Box 6)
      - 11 Sept. 1988; About Maggie, Who Tried Too Hard, review of Breathing Lessons by Edward Hoagland (Box 6)
      - 25 Aug. 1991; The Accidental Convert, review of Saint Maybe by Jay Parini (Box 6)
  - Original Letters by Tyler
    - Typed letter, signed, 7 February 1979, to John Norbutt (Box 6)
    - Typed letter, signed, 9 November 1985, to bookseller Bernice Weiss (Box 6)
    - Autograph postcard, signed, 21 January 1989, to first edition dealer Bev Chaney (Box 6)